普拉特-惠特尼飞机公司
可靠的发动机
联合航空制造公司的部门
佛罗里达州研发中心
出品
RL-10火箭发动机
正在为NASA开发
RL-10火箭引擎
The RL-10 rocket engine,
半人马上面级和土星火箭系列的动力装置 是多年研发的成果
power plant for Centaur and Saturn, is the result of years of development.
是西方世界建造的最高性能引擎 使用安全可靠的液氢
The highest performance engine built in the free world uses safe, reliable, and dependable hydrogen.
为了维持RL-10的高可靠性 重要部件需要在严格的实验室环境中装配
To maintain the high degree of reliability of the RL-10, vital parts are assembled under stringent laboratory conditions.
推力室管束按照典型的引擎装配流程进行安装
Following a typical engine through its paces, the thrust chamber tubes are installed.
将装配体放在心轴上后 就可以将歧管和加强带安装上去
After the assembly is placed over a mandrel the manifolds and bands can be attached.
用于炉中钎焊的银焊丝被铺设
Silver wire is laid in for furnace brazing.
推力室被放在一个蒸馏器中 做好了进炉的准备
Placed in a retort, the chamber is readied for the furnace.
一旦在炉中焖好 推力室会进行测试以确保无故障运行
Once braised the chamber undergoes testing to assure trouble-free operation.
液氮被打入推力室进行温度冲击试验
Liquid nitrogen is forced through the chamber to perform thermal shock tests.
用氮气进行加压 检查推力室是否有泄漏
Pressurized with gaseous nitrogen the chamber is checked for leaks.
检验过的子组件在特殊的烘箱中烘干
The inspected sub-assembly is dried out in a special oven.
喷注器安装完成后 推力室组装完成
Final chamber assembly is completed with the installation of the injector.
为了准确地对齐喷注器 特制的夹具被降了下来
A special jig is lowered to accurately align the injector.
然后在组装完整的发动机之前 对推力室进行最终加工
Then the chamber goes for final machining prior to assembly of the complete engine.
在装配楼层 所有部件汇聚集在一起
On the Assembly floor, all parts come together.
燃料管线 阀门 涡轮泵从无尘室运来 组装 安装然后检查
Fuel lines, valves, turbo pumps are brought from clean rooms assembled installed and inspected.
对每个部件和子组件进行多次检查 确保最大的可靠性
Multiple inspections of each component and sub assembly assures maximum reliability.
准备运行前 完成的引擎必须经过点火测试
Ready for action the completed engine must undergo the test of firing.
RL-10已经做好准备 可以运往试验场
The RL-10 is made ready for transport to the test site.
这个简单的图能很好地说明RL-10的工作原理
The operating principle of the RL-10 can best be shown by this simple diagram.
液氢在37兰氏度(-423华氏度)(-252.2℃)时从进给截断阀进入
Hydrogen at 37 degrees rankine minus 423 degrees Fahrenheit enters through the inlet shutoff valve.
通过第一级泵进入第二级泵
Passes through the first stage pump into the second stage pump
以每平方英寸1,000磅 (6.9MPa) 的压强排出
where it is discharged at 1,000 pounds per square inch.
然后它通过冷却歧管套 再通过束管的一半
Then it passes through the cooling jacket manifold through half of the tubes.
经过转弯歧管 反回到长束管 来到出口歧管
Through the turnaround manifold back through the long tubes to the exit manifold
然后通过文氏管进入涡轮
and through the venturi into the turbine.
此时的氢燃料已是每平方英寸850磅 (5.9MPa) 的气体了
At this point, the hydrogen is now gas at 850 pounds per square inch
温度在350兰氏度(-110华氏度)(-78.9℃)
and 350 degrees Rankine, minus 110 degrees Fahrenheit
膨胀后的氢燃料提供驱动氢泵和氧泵的动力
and provides the power to drive the hydrogen and oxygen pumps.
然后它通过主截断阀进入喷注器再进到燃烧室
It then goes through the main shutoff valve into the injector and to the combustion chamber.
液氧通过单级氧泵流入进给阀
Drawn in through the single stage oxygen pump, oxygen flows through the inlet valve.
直接通过混合比调节阀进入喷注器 与燃烧室内的氢气结合
Directly through the mixture ratio control valve into the injector to combine with the hydrogen in the chamber.
发动机本身就像图表那样简单
The engine itself is as simple as the diagram
展示液氢在此处通过第一级泵流向第二级泵
to demonstrate hydrogen enters at this point flows through the first stage pump into the second stage pump
通过冷却歧管套 往下过束管的一半 经过转弯歧管 往上到长束管
passes through the cooling jacket manifold down through half the tubes to the turnaround manifold up the long tubes
集中于出口歧管
collected at the exit manifold
经过文氏管进入涡轮
through the venturi into the turbine.
在那里它提供驱动氢泵和氧泵的动力
There it provides the power to drive the hydrogen and oxygen pumps.
然后绕过大管路 通过主燃料截断阀进入喷注器 再到燃烧室
Then around the large line through the main fuel shutoff valve into the injector and then to the combustion chamber.
液氧这边
On the oxygen side,
液氧通过单级氧泵流入进给阀
oxygen flows through the inlet valve through a single stage pump
直接通过混合比调节阀进入喷注器
directly through the mixture ratio control valve into the injector
到达其中一个垂直测试台 RL-10被安装好 准备进行试点火
Arriving at one of the vertical test stands, the RL-10 is installed and made ready for test firing.
会模拟太空点火环境
Spaced firing conditions will be simulated.
蒸汽喷射系统会将压力降低到接近宇宙的真空
A steam injector system lowers the pressure to the near vacuum of space.
在完成这项试点火后
On completion of this test firing,
发动机将被送回制造区进行完整的拆卸检查和重新组装
the engine will be returned to the manufacturing area for complete disassembly inspection and reassembly.
多年来 普惠公司
Years of experience, research and development
在设计和制造RL-10火箭引擎的过程中积累了丰富的经验和研发成果
have gone into the design and manufacture of the Pratt & Whitney aircraft RL-10 rocket engines.
RL-10还在NASA刘易斯研究中心进行了太空环境测试
The RL-10 is also undergone space condition testing at the NASA Lewis Research Center
现在改名为格伦研究中心
那里的特殊观察口允许对太空环境点火进行持续的目视检查
where special viewing ports permit continual visual check of space condition firing.
普惠公司的全天候研发项目正帮助加快美国的航天工作
Pratt & Whitney Aircraft's around-the-clock development program is helping accelerate the United States space efforts.